<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homepage on Conner Murphy</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Homepage on Conner Murphy</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smurphy000.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A return to writing</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/articles/getting-back-to-writing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smurphy000.github.io/articles/getting-back-to-writing/</guid><description>Originally, I began my portfolio / blog site back in 2021 towards the beginning of my career. However, I only ever attempted to write a few times, as I was never really been one to put content out in the open. As I continue to grow in my career, I have began to realize how important it is to write things down. Not just ones thoughts, but also learn how to explain things clearly.</description></item><item><title>Professional Experience</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/portfolio/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smurphy000.github.io/portfolio/about/</guid><description>I am a Software/Data Engineer with 5+ years of experience and I have a passion for developing and utilizing cutting edge technologies related to data processing and distributed computing. I enjoy contributing to open source projects, and learning new things about software and the technology industry.
Senior Data Engineer | Capital One Data Engineer | Hexagon PPM Education Certifications Senior Data Engineer | Capital One November 2021 - Present
At Capital One I work(ed) in the Software LOB where I was a member of multiple teams working to build a SaaS application called Slingshot.</description></item><item><title>Obtaining my first certification</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/articles/certifications/first-certification/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smurphy000.github.io/articles/certifications/first-certification/</guid><description>My first professional certification I had never really thought about getting a professional certification, until it was highly encouraged by upper management at my current company. At first I thought it would be a relatively easy thing to achieve, but after learning more about it, I became uncertain. The certification I was going for was the AWS Certified Solution Architect - Associate, and to achieve this, it required passing an exam consisting of 65 questions and scoring 720 or higher out of 1000.</description></item><item><title>Contributing to Open Source</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/articles/contrib-opensource/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smurphy000.github.io/articles/contrib-opensource/</guid><description>Contributing to Open Source I want to start this off by saying that it is hard to contribute to open source projects, at least for me. Contributing has always seemed kind of illusive, but also something that I have wanted to do for a while. The most difficult part for me (I think) is how I might seem to others, whenever I be create an issue, submit a pull request, or even just comment on a project.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Contributions</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/portfolio/oss-contrib/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smurphy000.github.io/portfolio/oss-contrib/</guid><description>delta-io/delta-rs Description: Library containing Rust APIs for accessing Delta tables. Also contains bindings for higher-level languages such as Python.
Contributions: Worked on creating new functionality in the Rust API, including a low level create table method.
apache/arrow-datafusion Description: Query execution framework using Apache Arrow as its in-memory format. Supports both SQL and DataFrame APIs.
Contributions: Modified schema checking for parquet files, so differing metadata would be ignored.</description></item></channel></rss>