<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conner Murphy</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Conner Murphy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smurphy000.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Obtaining my first certification</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/posts/first-certification/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smurphy000.github.io/posts/first-certification/</guid><description>My first professional certification I had never really thought about getting a professional certification, until it was highly encouraged by upper management at my current company. At first I thought it would be a relatively easy thing to achieve, but after learning more about it, I became uncertain. The certification I was going for was the AWS Certified Solution Architect - Associate, and to achieve this, it required passing an exam consisting of 65 questions and scoring 720 or higher out of 1000.</description></item><item><title>My Job Search</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/posts/job-search/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smurphy000.github.io/posts/job-search/</guid><description>In search of a new job I began my search for my second full-time job during September of 2021. I knew that at my current position, I was not reaching my full potential in compensation (very underpaid) and decided I needed to do what was best to better provide for my family. The current landscape for finding a job seems to be quite rough, however, I have been fortunate in my recent search.</description></item><item><title>Contributing to Open Source</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/posts/contrib-opensource/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smurphy000.github.io/posts/contrib-opensource/</guid><description>Contributing to Open Source I want to start this off by saying that it is hard to contribute to open source projects, at least for me. Contributing has always seemed kind of illusive, but also something that I have wanted to do for a while. The most difficult part for me (I think) is how I might seem to others, whenever I be create an issue, submit a pull request, or even just comment on a project.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smurphy000.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Contact Email
Connect LinkedIn
Collaborate Github</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smurphy000.github.io/about/</guid><description>I am a Data Engineer with 3+ years of work experience and I have a passion for developing and utilizing cutting edge technologies related to data processing and distributed computing. I enjoy contributing to open source projects, and learning new things about software and the technology industry.
Work Experience Data Engineer at Capital One | November 2021 - Present
Languages: Java, SQL, Python Technologies: GRPC Cloud: AWS, Snowflake, Github Data Engineer at Hexagon PPM | August 2019 - November 2021</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/posts/initial-post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smurphy000.github.io/posts/initial-post/</guid><description>Welcome! My name is Conner Murphy and I am a software/data engineer. I am will be using my personal website to also write some blog posts (mostly for my own benefit) to document my learning and research, but maybe you can get some value out of these posts as well!
Direction The current direction for this blog will about my continued learning in different programming languages such as:
Rust: because it is strongly typed, low level, high performance, up-and-coming language for data engineering Scala: because it is a functional, strongly typed, and jvm based language used in many big data technologies Also, I will be doing experimentation and research with new packages/libraries in the data space including Delta Lake, Spark, Datafusion, and more!</description></item><item><title>Portfolio</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/portfolio/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smurphy000.github.io/portfolio/</guid><description>Personal Projects Delta Viewer - Paused Development Description: Delta Viewer is an application for connecting to storage backends containing Delta tables and providing a managable interface for users to interact with table metadata and transactions. Open Source delta-io/delta-rs - Contributor Description: Library containing Rust APIs for accessing Delta tables. Also contains bindings for higher-level languages such as Python.
Contributions: Worked on creating new functionality in the Rust API, including a low level create table method.</description></item></channel></rss>