<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Conner Murphy</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Conner Murphy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smurphy000.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Job Search</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/posts/job-search/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smurphy000.github.io/posts/job-search/</guid><description>In search of a new job I began my search for my second full-time job during September of 2021. I knew that at my current position, I was not reaching my full potential in compensation (very underpaid) and decided I needed to do what was best to better provide for my family. The current landscape for finding a job seems to be quite rough, however, I have been fortunate in my recent search.</description></item><item><title>Contributing to Open Source</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/posts/contrib-opensource/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smurphy000.github.io/posts/contrib-opensource/</guid><description>Contributing to Open Source I want to start this off by saying that it is hard to contribute to open source projects, at least for me. Contributing has always seemed kind of illusive, but also something that I have wanted to do for a while. The most difficult part for me (I think) is how I might seem to others, whenever I be create an issue, submit a pull request, or even just comment on a project.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://smurphy000.github.io/posts/initial-post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smurphy000.github.io/posts/initial-post/</guid><description>Welcome! My name is Conner Murphy and I am a software/data engineer. I am will be using my personal website to also write some blog posts (mostly for my own benefit) to document my learning and research, but maybe you can get some value out of these posts as well!
Direction The current direction for this blog will about my continued learning in different programming languages such as:</description></item></channel></rss>